## Cesar Augusto Martinez Auquilla

841 Flagler Drive, Gaithersburg, 20878, Maryland

Phone: 202 306 2469 (Mobil) E-mail: <a href="mailto:cesaguma@hotmail.com">cesaguma@hotmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/cesar-augusto-martinez-auguilla-03934a16b">linkedin.com/in/cesar-augusto-martinez-auguilla-03934a16b</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/CesarAugustoMartinez">https://github.com/CesarAugustoMartinez</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://cesaraugustomartinez.github.io/Portfolio/">https://cesaraugustomartinez.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

# Full-Stack Web Developer with a Bachelor's degree in Systems Engineering and a proven database and GIS background.

**Full-Stack Web Developer with a Bachelor's degree in Systems Engineering and a proven database and GIS background.** A graduate of Johns Hopkins University with a certificate in Full Stack Web Development expanding on programming languages and technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C++, PHP, and databases as Oracle, MySQL, and Access. Ability to solve complex problems and track record as a General Manager and Co-owner of Msportswear. Demonstrated experience managing projects for IT systems and manufacturing processes using the latest technologies in this area.

A penchant professional with an aptitude to work independently and collaboratively to drive feasible outcomes under pressure. Looking to leverage web development and database; to create intuitive apps to help people and improve systems. Education and Experience

#### **Technical Skills**

- Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Access, SQL Server.
- **Developer Programs**: Oracle JDeveloper 11g, Visual Basic 6.0, ASP.NET (Web Forms, MVC), Visual C++, Dreamweaver, Oracle Forms, MySQL Workbench, Data Warehouse, NetLogo 4.1.3, Node Js.
- Geographic Information Systems: Arcgis 9.3, Arcgis 10.0, ArcScene 10.0, ENVI, IDRISI SELVA
- **Programming Languages**: Java, C++, HTML5, PHP, BASIC, JavaScript, jQuery.
- CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Materialize.
- Networking Protocols: DNS, DHCP, HTTP, OSPF, EIGRP, TFTP, Frame Relay, ATM2
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MAC OS

## **Projects**

#### **Trail Mixer**

**GitHub:** <a href="https://lucasbryg.github.io/Group-Project-1/">https://lucasbryg.github.io/Group-Project-1/</a>

Deployed Project: <a href="https://github.com/lucasBRYG/Group-Project-1">https://github.com/lucasBRYG/Group-Project-1</a>

The goal of this project was the creation of a web application where hiking, biking, running, and ski trails info can be found nearby user's location. The user can explore new trails as well as get a general idea of what the trail entails.

In charge of the complete back-end and front-end development to gather all data from third party APIs and display the most accurate data search for final user.

#### **Technologies**

- Html5
- jQuery

- Visual Studio Code
- Materialize Framework
- Open Weather API
- Hiking Project API

## **Education and Experience**

#### John Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD

**Bootcamp Certificate,** A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

## Montgomery College, Maryland – United States

Cisco CCNA Certification, December 2019, Cisco CCNA Routing and Switching.

# University of Azuay, Cuenca - Ecuador 2011: Bachelors - Information Systems Engineering US Degree equivalence evaluation from WES available upon request

**Most Important Projects** 

- Created Web-based application for the administrative control of a sports academy (The Inline Speed Skating Federation of Azuay, an Ecuadorian province)
  - Database: MySQL
  - o Programming Language: Oracle JDeveloper 11g
  - o This application was the final Project for graduation in Information Systems Engineering
  - o Received perfect score for this final Project from the faculty
- Created Information Management System for the Water Utility in Cuenca, Ecuador
  - Database: MySQL
  - Programming Language: PHP

#### **Technologies and Systems**

- Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Access, SQL Server.
- **Developer Programs**: Oracle JDeveloper 11g, Visual Basic 6.0, ASP.NET (Web Forms, MVC), Visual C++, Prolog, Dreamweaver, Oracle Forms, MySQL Workbench, Data Warehouse, NetLogo 4.1.3
- Geographic Information Systems: Arcgis 9.3, Arcgis 10.0, ArcScene 10.0, ENVI, IDRISI SELVA
- Programming Languages: Java,C++, XML, HTML, PHP, ADF, BASIC, JavaScript,
- Networking Protocols: DNS, DHCP, HTTP, OSPF, EIGRP, TFTP, Frame Relay, ATM2
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MAC OS

#### University of Azuay, Cuenca – Ecuador

Masters Candidate, May 2014, Geographic Information Systems with emphasis on Land Planning

• Completed Master's curriculum

## **GIS Projects**

- Created environmental management plan to identify site for waste transfer station in Cuenca, Ecuador
  - Location for the landfill identified by this project was implemented by the municipality
  - Used Geographic Information Systems such as ARCGIS 10.0, ARCSCENE 10.0
- Created dynamic model to simulate effect of dam breakage on a surrounding area using NetLogo 4.1.3
- Collaborated in creation of the Land Plan of the City of Cuenca, Ecuador

#### GIS Knowledge/Experience

- Spatial reference systems and Global satellite navigation systems
- Aerial Photographs and Photo restoration
- Geodatabases and network analysis
- Satellite Teledetection and Teledetection Sensors
- Temporal Analysis of Teledetection Output
- Exploratory Analysis of Spatial Data and Infrastructure for Spatial Data and Map Servers
- Advanced Analysis of Geographic Data (socioeconomic variables)
- Cartographic Quality Control, Land Surveys, and Valuation
- Management and Use of Hidrographic Bodies
- Environmental Protection, Land Use Planning, and Assessment and Restructuring

## Hermano Miguel "La Salle" High School, 2003 - Physics/Math

- Worked as Visual Basic programmer at the "Center of Information Systems Studies" Sponsored by the University of Cambridge, 2003
- Studied in the Physics and Math Specialization Program

Languages: English - High level of written and Medium level of spoken; Spanish - Native

## Professional Experience

#### Full-Stack Web Developer of Msportswear USA, Maryland - EEUU 2018-present

- Website developer and administrator attracted new customers with website and social media enhancements.
- Implemented database system to manage clothes inventory for the web page.
- Developing mobile app.
- Web site: http://www.martinezsportswear.com/

## Support Staff - Fitzgerald Auto Mall, Gaithersburg - Maryland Nov, 2018-present

- Update Web site information as new cars stock pictures and videos
- Stocking New Cars
- Assist with customer reception
- Interchanges between dealers
- Valet completed vehicles for waiting customers

### General Manager, Co-Owner of Msportswear Ltd, Cuenca - Ecuador 2012-2018

- Created family owned company while studying for Master's degree
- Manage projects for IT systems and manufacturing processes using the latest technologies
- Oversee production of high-quality competition clothing for high-endurance athletes
- Income and production grew 300% between 2012 and 2013, 100% from 2015 to 2016 and 100% from 2016 to 2017
- Web site: http://www.martinezsportswear.com/

## Systems Engineer – "Hogar del Ecuador" Foundation, Cuenca - Ecuador, www.funhogar.org

- Hosting and Network administrator
- Website developer and administrator attracted new customers with website and social media enhancements.

## Systems Engineer – 96.9 Radio Familia, Cuenca - Ecuador,

- Hosting and Network administrator
- Online Radio developer and administrator –attracted new customers with website and social media enhancements.

## Other Accomplishments

## Inline Speed-Skating Champion

- Elite In-line Speed Skater, 2002 2011
  - National Champion in various speed and distance events
  - o Represent Provincial and National Teams for International Competitions from 2002 through 2011
- Skating Coach, Sports Federation of Azuay, 2014 (Cuenca, Ecuador)
- Skating Coach, Hnos. Martinez Speed Skating Club, 2018 (Cuenca, Ecuador)